

Joseph Hettich

Email: Joe@Doczine.com History: Resume or CV Online Phone: (805)252-0143

Cover Letter

I have been using and creating HTML and CSS sites since 2002. I have been using and administering PHP applications since 2004, and programming them since 2009. I wrote the JQuery, Javascript, PHP and MySQL for Doczine.com.

I regularly build dynamic web applications using up to date visual display methods, and I regularly browse sites like Drupal, Github, Stack Overflow and Google Code for updates on technologies in the front and backend.

I have a long history in data analysis, database modeling, programming, systems engineering and design. I have been using spreadsheet applications since Excel 95. I am good at writing technical specifications and software design documentation, because I studied it and other technical knowledge at Azusa Pacific University and Santa Barbara City College.

Technical Support Engineer

Work Experience

iCRco Inc. | Goleta, California

MARCH 2016 - JUNE 2017

- Remote access support for Clarity PACS and XC via TeamViewer
- CentOS Linux server remote command line support

Hardware and Software support for DR and CR medical devices

· Handle supervisor call escalations

Customer Retention

Support phone calls for Garcinia Lean Xtreme and Nature Renew

Rev3nue LLC | Carpinteria, California

OCTOBER 2014 - FEBRUARY 2016

JULY 2013 - DECEMBER 2013

JULY 2012 - PRESENT

- Database CRM processing
- Customer retention

Managed project specifications and development for eTriever student advising software

Application Engineer

UC Berkeley | Berkeley, California

• Wrote PDF editing software which allowed existing advising PDFs to be integrated into HTML 5 web forms • Wrote software to interface with Oracle 12 databases through PHP OCI connectors

• Consulted and commented on UC wide software and hardware system upgrades

Wrote faceted comment search application for eTriever student advising application

Wrote PHP and MySQL scripts for the site wide system

Doczine.com | Las Vegas, Nevada

· Wrote original design specifications and code

Software Architect

• Wrote MySQL database structure and SQL database creation script Wrote JQuery and Javascript for upload form and home page

- Wrote infinite scroll script for home page, and user file list pages • Maintained, upgraded, and installed Ubuntu and FreeBSD servers
- · Created file upload and conversion algorithm
- Created document web crawler Integrated Solr based search engine
- Configured PFSense router and firewall
- IT Manager Troy Capital LLC. | Las Vegas, Nevada

Managed, fixed and maintained the Collect! collection database Wrote custom reports using Collect! collections database

Maintained group drive data backups, off-site server backups, Ghost desktop backups

FEB 2013 - AUG 2013

 Integrated You've Got Claims data with the Collect! database Processed and integrated Experian credit bureau reports into Collect!

Managed Windows Server 2008 servers, and Windows 7 and Vista desktops

- Managed projects to upgrade the company's infrastructure · Managed network upgrades, and built IP camera monitoring system

Managed item data integration process for new and existing item sellers • Assisted sellers with integrating data using Soap API, CSV, XLS, XML data sources

Data Integration Analyst

• Managed large item lists and troubleshot errors with item integration

Newegg Marketplace | Industry, California

JUNE 2011 - NOV 2011

• Worked with development team to find and fix errors with the integration process Helped tracked and find bugs in the Newegg Marketplace seller portal

• Created weekly and monthly statistic reports on integration progress for sellers

- Created OLAP reports to track system errors and integration progress • Extensive work with Excel spreadsheets and SharePoint reporting and tracking
- Studied sellers web applications in order to provide solutions on how to better integrate their data with the Newegg Marketplace database
- Data Manager MAY 2010 - APR 2011

Managed email auto-responder platform integrated into lead database

• Managed the creation of new lists, column mappings, and providers in the lead database • Managed CSV, CSV email and real time exports leaving the lead database

• Created technical and user documentation for job processes

AdMax Media Inc. | Santa Barbara, California

JAN 2009 - JUL 2010

 Created lead analysis reports used to launch a new SMS marketing campaign Calculated and approved invoices for call center and Discount Lead Network media buys

• Managed lead buying and delivery process for two education lead generation call centers

• Co-managed Discount Lead Network lead reselling division of AdMax Media

 Created reports that measured data needs based on man hours and number of dials Wrote use cases in JIRA in order to add new features in the lead management database • Helped Director of Engineering to document bugs in the lead management database

• Managed weekly and monthly call center media buy reports education campaigns

- Used pivot tables querying OLAP cubes to create dynamic dialer reports to analyze performance metrics over periods of time
- Billing Coordinator Aeria Games and Entertainment | San Jose, California

Researched fraudulent transaction activity in Aeria Games billing admin system

Responded and tracked Google and PayPal chargebacks correspondance

· Reviewed fraudulent IP address activity reports

Reconciled Google and PayPal chargebacks and balances

Responded to billing email inquiries in email ticketing system

· Awarded and compiled reports for events, rebates and promotions

 Researched other micro-transaction billing systems Created and compiled ad-hoc Excel reports and statistic calculations Tested payment options on the billing test site and helped develop test documentation

Coordinated with other teams to mitigate and combat fraudulent accounts

Filed JIRA bug tickets to implement new features or when software issues arose

Ran fraud reports through an internal reporting system in combination with Excel

Corresponded with customers to verify high dollar, and suspicious looking transactions

information linked to duplicate fraudulent accounts, ran Melissa data lookups Tracked American Express and Paymentech chargebacks using Excel

- Created and ran complex Macro express and VBA macros to automate receptive tasks
- Sr. Fraud Prevention Specialist Citrix Online | Santa Barbara, California

High volume of account analysis required the ability to find inconsistencies in large quantities of data. ~200 accounts a day,

MAR 2005 - SEP 2005

sometimes more depending on report and frequency • Helped make decisions and suggestions for new tools and policy changes in response to the ever changing carder and fraud attempts

solutions, paperwork and facsimiles

Large amounts of Excel, Word, Outlook and PDF editing and correspondence, Updated Excel report formulas

Researched fraudulent transaction activity in GoToMyPC and GoToMeeting customer database in real-time

High volume of merchant chargeback correspondence with American Express and Paymentech using merchant ecommerce

Citrix Online | Santa Barbara, California Handled technical support phone calls for GoToMyPC and GoToMeeting

• Dealt with general account modifications, refunds, edits, purchases etc.

· Coordinated meetings and duties through Outlook, Excel, Word · Worked in a high tech call center with a high volume of calls

- Walked customers through ordering online Handled technical support emails for GoToMyPC and GoToMeeting through internal ticketing system
- Online Customer Support Representative Bargain Network Inc. | Santa Barbara, California

Assisted customers over phone, with technical/non-technical support questions

• Respond to emails regarding technical support, general customer support, and general website servicing questions

• Evaluated beta customer support application upgrades • Dealt with usual users level apps, worked in excel, email applets, chat applets, customer support apps, web apps, intranet,

database etc.

Education

· Process account maintenance, refunds, editing, auditing and account modifications requests

Management Information Systems Bachelors

Azusa Pacific University

Santa Barbara City College Associates of Science in Computer Information Systems

• Ran IP/DNS reports on fraudulent accounts, ran reverse phone lookups, IP matching, ran manual checks on IP and other

SEPT 2005 - JUN 2008

- **Customer Care Representative**
- Used the remote support application GoToAssist to troubleshoot GoToMyPC and GoToMeeting web applications. (GoToMyPC.com, GoToMeeting.com etc.)
 - FEB 2002 MAR 2005

• Respond to Live Online Agent Chat requests, regarding technical support questions and general servicing questions